<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>connectivity on Jonifen 👨‍💻</title><link>/tags/connectivity/</link><description>Recent content in connectivity on Jonifen 👨‍💻</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>(c) 2020 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 21:33:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/connectivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TP-Link Archer C2 - First Impressions</title><link>/blog/tplink-archer-c2-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 21:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/tplink-archer-c2-first-impressions/</guid><description>As mentioned in my last post, I was in the hunt for a new router to replace the aging Buffalo WHR-HP-G54. I&amp;rsquo;d found that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t capable of handling fibre broadband speeds (hardly surprising&amp;hellip; given that it&amp;rsquo;s running a 200MHz single core CPU with barely a few megs free of the 16Mb RAM).
I ended up dropping by PC World and picking up the TP-Link Archer C2 for £49.99 (a few quid more expensive than it was at Scan, but PC World was closer, so I was saving petrol money and around 30 minutes of my time for the round-trip).</description></item><item><title>Buffalo WHR-HP-G54 Fun (or not...)</title><link>/blog/buffalo-whr-hp-g54/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 22:54:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/buffalo-whr-hp-g54/</guid><description>Out of contract with my previous supplier, I was free to find a new supplier. Luckily, one of the benefits of my job is that I get free fibre broadband, so it was a simple decision :)
Anyway, back to the point of my post.
I last used the Buffalo a few years back when on Virgin Media&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;National&amp;rdquo; service (no longer available - a good thing as it was trash) when their supplied Netgear had weak wi-fi.</description></item><item><title>No dial tone, but broadband still works?</title><link>/blog/no-dial-tone-but-broadband-works/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 20:58:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/no-dial-tone-but-broadband-works/</guid><description>It seems whenever I need to make a phone call on the landline, it&amp;rsquo;s broken. Yesterday I picked up the landline handset and it was dead. No dial tone. Nothing. Nada. Zip.
I tried the usual steps at first (unplug it, plug it back in) but no joy. Onto the broadband I went. Works fine. Weird. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this before and leaving stuff unplugged overnight seemed to fix it, but on this occasion it didn&amp;rsquo;t help.</description></item></channel></rss>