<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>React on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</title><link>/tags/react/</link><description>Recent content in React on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 17:30:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Storybook JS: 'Cannot GET /'</title><link>/blog/2021/storybookjs-cannot-get-root/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 17:30:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/storybookjs-cannot-get-root/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When you run storybook locally, you might encounter the error &amp;lsquo;Cannot GET /&amp;rsquo; when browsing to localhost:6006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general advice given online is to delete all node modules for your project and re-install the packages using your preferred package manager. However, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t always solve the problem and I was in this position just a moment ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, in the &lt;a href="https://storybook.js.org/docs/react/api/cli-options"&gt;Storybook CLI docs&lt;/a&gt;, there is an argument &lt;code&gt;--no-manager-cache&lt;/code&gt; which says that it will disable the Storybook manager caching mechanism. They recommend not using this every time you run it, but it&amp;rsquo;ll help when you need to refresh the Storybook UI, such as when editing themes etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to test a custom React hook component</title><link>/blog/react-js-test-custom-hook-component/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 10:20:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/react-js-test-custom-hook-component/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my GameBrowser side-project, I&amp;rsquo;m at the stage where I wanted to start improving the UI a bit. This included needing to define a way of filtering the servers in the list, because they&amp;rsquo;re all saved together at the moment. As a first attempt, I opted for a simple Dropdown control and decided to make it generic using a custom React Hook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was the creation of &lt;code&gt;useDropdown&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Basic Setup for React Projects in 2020</title><link>/blog/basic-setup-for-react-projects-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 11:26:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/basic-setup-for-react-projects-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of people using project initialisation tools to create their new React projects over the years, in particular &lt;code&gt;create-react-app&lt;/code&gt;. While I do see there are some benefits to these tools (in particular for newcomers), these tools do have their disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cloned a repository the other day which was using create-react-app, and an &lt;code&gt;npm i&lt;/code&gt; installed over 2000 packages! This is a hell of a lot to download just to be able to run some code locally. Yes, these packages will be cached, but if you take into account the time it takes for one dev, multiply that across a team of devs (also accounting for devs trashing their local repos and re-cloning), this could be a reasonable bit of time lost. This time is often lost at times where developers are feeling most productive too.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>