<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</title><link>/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 20:13:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows 8/10 computer not connecting to your network?</title><link>/blog/windowsupdate_dhcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 20:13:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/windowsupdate_dhcp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a fair few people lately telling me that their Windows computers are struggling to connect to the Internet. After doing some digging into the problem, it turns out that it could be related to a failed Windows Update that Microsoft initially issued in December 2016, but some computers are slow in picking up the update (or the owners are similar to me, and don&amp;rsquo;t reboot very often to let updates take effect!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dell Vostro 3350 Laptop with Windows 10</title><link>/blog/dell-vostro-3350-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 22:32:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/dell-vostro-3350-windows-10/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So this week I&amp;rsquo;ve bought an ex-corporate Dell Vostro 3350 with the intention of it replacing Di&amp;rsquo;s aged Pentium D desktop which is struggling since the Windows 10 upgrade.
The laptop came pre-installed with Windows 10 Professional (a digital entitlement upgrade from the Windows 7 Pro that came on the laptop), and seemed quick enough. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not one to use a laptop as it comes, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s not brand new. Plus I noticed some of the devices weren&amp;rsquo;t installed correctly, so I took the opportunity to reinstall on the mechanical disk to ensure I have the right drivers before reinstalling onto the SSD that&amp;rsquo;ll come out of the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Windows Update Error 8007000E</title><link>/blog/windows-update-error-8007000e-clean-install/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 20:14:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/windows-update-error-8007000e-clean-install/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Twice recently I&amp;rsquo;ve reinstalled Windows 7 on a machine, only for Windows Update to fail when checking for updates. On both machines it gave an error 8007000E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first machine (belonging to my nephew), I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fix, so left it with him with automatic updates enabled in the hope it&amp;rsquo;ll fix itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second machine is this Samsung netbook. As it&amp;rsquo;s already had me over a barrel, it won&amp;rsquo;t do me over again! So onto the Internets I went&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not alone here, as there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of machines in a similar situation. But luckily, Henk Hoogendoorn has blogged about it over at &lt;a href="http://henkhoogendoorn.blogspot.co.uk/2015/10/some-clients-not-updating-reporting.html"&gt;http://henkhoogendoorn.blogspot.co.uk/2015/10/some-clients-not-updating-reporting.html&lt;/a&gt; and suggested that it needs a further Windows Update and a cheeky config change to get it to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Windows XP and it's poor effort of an "Automatic Updates" service</title><link>/blog/windows-xp-dodgy-automatic-updates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/windows-xp-dodgy-automatic-updates/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s the end of a long Sunday which started later than expected (as I&amp;rsquo;d slept in despite my son&amp;rsquo;s best efforts to wake me with the ever-loud playback of YouTube videos). I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of the day glaring at a computer screen but not for productive gain as it&amp;rsquo;s my family duty to fix the broken computers of the children/parents/siblings, except this time it&amp;rsquo;s been a looonnnnggg job which Windows XP is just aching to make so much worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>