<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on Jon Cain</title>
    <link>/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on Jon Cain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2020 Jon Cain</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 21:27:47 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Revert a range of commits in a Git repository</title>
      <link>/blog/git-revert-range-of-commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 21:27:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/git-revert-range-of-commits/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had one of those days when you&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work on a repository, making small and regular commits to the repository during the day only to decide that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the way you wanted to go? So how do you get back to where you were at the beginning of the day?
Well, you could just revert each commit one-by-one, but what if your commit history is like this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git reverts without automatic commit</title>
      <link>/blog/git-revert-without-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 21:52:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/git-revert-without-commit/</guid>
      <description>Git is easily the best source control system I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used, yet it&amp;rsquo;s probably one of the more infuriating too because its power and flexibility can also land the users in a whole world of pain.
Today at work we had a scenario where a colleague needed to revert a handful of commits including a merge but there was a chance it may need re-introducing at a later date. I suggested reverting each commit with --no-commit but nobody else had heard of this argument before, hence I felt a post may be useful (although this probably requires that people visit my blog first to find it haha).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>