<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</title><link>/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:46:16 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Built My Custom Hugo Pagination</title><link>/blog/how-i-built-my-custom-hugo-pagination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:46:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-i-built-my-custom-hugo-pagination/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning on improving the pagination control for my blog for some time, but it always seemed a bigger job than I really wanted to work on in my spare time, but I was wrong. The only complexity was around the weird templating syntax that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; got to grips with fully yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did some research first, why re-invent the wheel right? And I came across a &lt;a href="https://glennmccomb.com/articles/how-to-build-custom-hugo-pagination/"&gt;really good tutorial from Glenn McComb&lt;/a&gt; where he went through how he built his, and seeing his examples, along with his explanations, made the syntax sink in better. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend giving his page a read first, as mine is based upon his with a few changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>View Hugo served content on another device on network</title><link>/blog/view-hugo-served-content-on-lan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 14:18:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/view-hugo-served-content-on-lan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When you want to view content served by a locally running instance of Hugo on another device, you have to specify a few extra things so it will work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start the Hugo server locally, it will show the following output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo server -w
...
(some output omitted here for brevity)
...
Web Server is available at //localhost:1313/ (bind address 127.0.0.1)
Press Ctrl+C to stop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s bound to your localhost IP, you can&amp;rsquo;t just open port 1313 on your computer via a firewall and access Hugo from another device. You have to bind Hugo to the network IP instead (To find out the IP, try &lt;code&gt;ipconfig&lt;/code&gt; on Windows or &lt;code&gt;ip a&lt;/code&gt; on Linux).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>