<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Jonifen 👨‍💻</title><link>/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Jonifen 👨‍💻</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>(c) 2020 Jon Cain</copyright><atom:link href="/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dell XPS 15 9530</title><link>/notes/dell-xps-15-9530/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/dell-xps-15-9530/</guid><description>Sluggy performance (CPU capped) This morning, I noticed that my Dell XPS 15 9530 felt a little sluggish, so did some investigation and found the CPU clock had capped at a lower speed. I did a full reboot of Windows 10, and luckily this was sufficient to shake things back into life. But a quick read online suggested that some people aren&amp;rsquo;t quite as lucky in this situation.
So if a reboot doesn&amp;rsquo;t resolve the issue, what next?</description></item><item><title>Git (Source Control)</title><link>/notes/git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/git/</guid><description>Retaining chmod permissions for scripts in git repositories git update-index --chmod=+x your_bash_script.sh The git documentation provides more information on the update-index command here: https://www.git-scm.com/docs/git-update-index
Revert without commit A standard git revert will create a new commit with the reverted content. To revert without creating that commit:
git revert {commit-id} --no-commit The changes will be staged ready for committing, but a git reset will unstage the changes, so you can continue making changes.</description></item><item><title>HP DM1-4027</title><link>/notes/hp-dm1-4027/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/hp-dm1-4027/</guid><description>Laptop locks up in Linux - thermal event I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started to use a HP DM1-4027ea as a replacement for the Asus Eee 1005P netbook. The 4Gb RAM (upgradable to 8Gb) and more powerful CPU/GPU combo meant that it should give reasonable performance where the Eee struggles (downloading npm modules and browsing script/image heavy websites).
The HP DM1-4027ea comes with an AMD E-450 APU which consists of a dual core 1.</description></item><item><title>Home DIY</title><link>/notes/home-diy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/home-diy/</guid><description>Developers probably aren&amp;rsquo;t typically known for their DIY ability in the home. I try to do a bit, but I know my limitations so these notes are mainly to remind me of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and what I used to do the job.
TV Installation (DIY) I&amp;rsquo;ve used the following items to install an aerial inside my loft space and then drop cables down in cavities or conduit buried in channels within the plaster.</description></item><item><title>Linux</title><link>/notes/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/linux/</guid><description>Most of the notes in here are Arch Linux specific, as this is the distro I use most and the one which tends to give me the most curveballs to deal with! But this is what&amp;rsquo;s so good about it, as it gives me a way to learn things better than I would do with one of the more common distros like Ubuntu.
If anyone reads any of these notes and thinks there&amp;rsquo;s a better way, please let me know - any help is always appreciated.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi</title><link>/notes/raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/raspberry-pi/</guid><description>Laggy mouse on Raspberry Pi (Model 1b) A few weeks ago I installed the latest (at the time) version of Raspbian onto a 4Gb SD Card thinking that I&amp;rsquo;d see whether it was worthwhile updating my main SD card or not. I gave it a quick run and while it seemed quicker, the mouse was quite laggy as if the cursor was moving through treacle. After a quick search, I came across a report on the RaspberryPi Github where someone else was having the exact same problem where the mouse was moving &amp;ldquo;in slow motion&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>SQL</title><link>/notes/sql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/sql/</guid><description>Joins I came across this diagram on Twitter a few weeks ago. I saved a copy intending to post it to my site (mainly for future reference) but since then I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten who actually posted it on Twitter. As such, I can&amp;rsquo;t give them a mention. If it was you, get in touch on Twitter and I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post with your details :)</description></item><item><title>Scanners</title><link>/notes/scanners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/scanners/</guid><description>PrimeFilm 1800u Film Scanner As part of the downsizing task my Mum has taken on, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of photos and slides to transfer to a digital format that can be viewed on an iPad (or digital photo frame). The photos is an easy task (albeit fairly monotonous as my scanner doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a document feeder), but the slides might be trickier.
My Mum bought a slide scanner a few years ago (OK then, quite a few years ago), the PrimeFilm 1800u Film Scanner.</description></item><item><title>Sky TV</title><link>/notes/sky-tv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/sky-tv/</guid><description> Sky Remote Codes Sky&amp;rsquo;s website provides some remote codes to work on TVs, but there are additional codes which might not be listed.
Brand/Model Sky&amp;rsquo;s Codes Working Code Comments JVC LT-42C550 0681/1846/1191 3830 Must be a Rev.10 remote (Thanks to Susan101 on the Sky Help Forum)</description></item></channel></rss>