<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>React-Native on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</title><link>/tags/react-native/</link><description>Recent content in React-Native on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 19:38:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/react-native/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>React Native &amp; Android: "Failed to Install the App"</title><link>/blog/2021/react-native-android-failed-to-install-the-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 19:38:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/react-native-android-failed-to-install-the-app/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been setting up a MacBook Pro to be able to work on a React Native mobile app and hit a stumbling block when running the Android app locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had already installed all the relevant applications needed (Android Studio, a JDK etc.) but when I ran &lt;code&gt;react-native run-android&lt;/code&gt;, it would give me the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;code&gt;error Failed to install the app. Make sure you have the Android development environment set up
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried a few different things until I came across &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/67360611/3157725"&gt;a solution proposed by Menon Hasan on Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; where they proposed the following command to set the executable permission on the &lt;code&gt;gradlew&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Testing Mobile App in AWS Device Farm using Appium and Node</title><link>/blog/2021/appium-node-aws-device-farm-react-native/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 11:02:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/appium-node-aws-device-farm-react-native/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning: this post is quite code heavy as I offer our solution as an example&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a mobile app for our customers. We&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at automated testing to interact with the app like a user would on a device and came across Appium and Detox as potential options that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost too much to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we primarily worked on Windows machines, Detox was out of the running as it seems to be only guaranteed support on MacOS, so we started looking at Appium instead. AWS Device Farm supports this already, so this looked promising and a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>