<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberrypi on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</title><link>/tags/raspberrypi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberrypi on Jon Cain (jonifen.co.uk)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 06:30:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/raspberrypi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows 10 IoT on a Raspberry Pi 2</title><link>/blog/pi2-windows10-iot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 06:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/pi2-windows10-iot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I thought it a good idea to spend some time looking at Windows 10 IoT edition on my Raspberry Pi 2. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at this since it was first announced a while back, but never actually got around to having a proper look into it and getting it installed on one of our Pis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kit do I have then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edimax EW-7811Un Nano USB Wireless Dongle (which turned out to be unsupported, but there is a workaround - details to come later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official Power Supply (the white Raspberry Pi 2.1A model)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all I need to get the operating system downloaded. I found the Windows IoT Dashboard software available for free from Microsoft (I downloaded it from &lt;a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/iot/Downloads.htm"&gt;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/iot/Downloads.htm&lt;/a&gt;) and installed it onto my laptop ready to go. This software allowed me to specify that it is intended for running on a Raspberry Pi (it lists the Pi 2 and 3 - I assume the Pi 1 isn&amp;rsquo;t powerful enough?) so I followed the steps and created my MicroSD card ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi on a 19" Widescreen (16:10) LCD Monitor</title><link>/blog/raspberrypi-19-widescreen-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/raspberrypi-19-widescreen-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I booked places for me and my son on a Raspberry Pi day in Manchester and then realised I might struggle to get the TV there as it&amp;rsquo;s pretty heavy, plus I doubt we&amp;rsquo;d be allowed it on a bus! Luckily, we still have the 19&amp;quot; widescreen from the old living room PC, so I looked at using that instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monitor was made by Daewoo, I got it about 6 years ago (or there abouts) and it has a native resolution of 1440x900 at a refresh rate of 60Hz.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi &amp; Hannspree 37" TV</title><link>/blog/raspberrypi-hannspree-tv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/raspberrypi-hannspree-tv/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough at Christmas for my wife to surprise me with a Raspberry Pi. I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted one for some time but never got around to actually ordering one. My wife always asks me when she&amp;rsquo;s faced with techie decisions which made it an even bigger surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last few days getting it up and running but my son realised earlier that it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have any sound coming through the TV set, so I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last couple of hours reading and trying stuff out and I think I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to the bottom of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>