<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mobilephones on Jonifen 👨‍💻</title><link>/tags/mobilephones/</link><description>Recent content in mobilephones on Jonifen 👨‍💻</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>(c) 2020 Jon Cain</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 13:38:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/mobilephones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iPhone requires Apple Id password on free downloads</title><link>/blog/apple-id-requires-password-for-free-download/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 13:38:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/apple-id-requires-password-for-free-download/</guid><description>For a while my son&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 5 has prompted for my Apple Id password everytime he tries to download a free app, or when updating his existing apps. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t always done this, so something must have changed. I had a look around online, comparing advice to the settings on his phone, and all seemed fine, but it still asked for this password.
Earlier this morning, I did a backup, a factory reset and a backup restore.</description></item><item><title>LG G3 - No fun here</title><link>/blog/lg-g3-possibly-the-worst-flagship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 22:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/lg-g3-possibly-the-worst-flagship/</guid><description>Edit 04/04/2016 I should have updated this post sooner. Usually I&amp;rsquo;d just include an addendum at the bottom, but I&amp;rsquo;ve re-worded a few bits in the content as my original review was maybe a tad harsh, and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why below. It&amp;rsquo;s just a shame it took so long for the Marshmallow update to be available, as I&amp;rsquo;d already had enough with the handset and wanted back to an Apple where things are just simple!</description></item><item><title>Going back to iPhone! Or maybe not...</title><link>/blog/going-back-to-iphone-or-maybe-not/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/going-back-to-iphone-or-maybe-not/</guid><description>My &amp;lsquo;love affair&amp;rsquo; (if you could ever call it that) with Android has always been a little rocky (as mentioned back in June) but I&amp;rsquo;m now ready to go back to an iPhone. Being a Dad, this time of year is never exactly the right time to blow out big money on a new phone for myself so that&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait for the new year. But I&amp;rsquo;ve got hold of my daughter&amp;rsquo;s old iPhone 5c to use in the meantime.</description></item><item><title>McAfee Mobile Security</title><link>/blog/mcafee-mobile-security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 08:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/mcafee-mobile-security/</guid><description>About a fortnight ago, I changed to an android handset after having iPhones for the last 4 years. I had decided on an LG G3 which turns out to come preinstalled with McAfee Mobile Security&amp;hellip; Which is fine&amp;hellip; Or would be if it worked properly.
I use an app for my online banking. When I load it up, it complains that there is no security product installed. If I open up McAfee manually, and go back into my banking app, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t complain.</description></item><item><title>Must review payment details when using an existing Apple Id on a new device</title><link>/blog/review-payment-details-existing-appleid-new-device/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 22:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/review-payment-details-existing-appleid-new-device/</guid><description>My daughter has this week got a new iPhone 5C and has been trying to download apps onto it. However, when she logs into her Apple ID on the 5C, she&amp;rsquo;s prompted to review her payment details. In the list that appears, there is no &amp;ldquo;None&amp;rdquo; option available, and she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to enter her card details (for which I don&amp;rsquo;t blame her - I haven&amp;rsquo;t entered mine on my Apple ID either!</description></item></channel></rss>