<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>csharp on Jon Cain</title>
    <link>/tags/csharp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in csharp on Jon Cain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2020 Jon Cain</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 13:18:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/csharp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Umbraco 7: Create a custom Property Editor</title>
      <link>/blog/umbraco-7-custom-property-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 13:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/umbraco-7-custom-property-editor/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on creating an implementation of Umbraco CMS for the Marketing team at work to use for quickly creating content for promotions etc. and the SEO Manager has asked what we could implement to benefit them in terms of SEO (Search Engine Optimisation for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know).
Requirements Now, until working on this, I knew what SEO was, but had no idea what it entailed, so working with the SEO Manager, we outlined the following requirements for our initial (MVP) release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribbon in .NET 4.5 using WPF and MVVM</title>
      <link>/blog/ribbon-in-net45-using-wpf-mvvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ribbon-in-net45-using-wpf-mvvm/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time recently to learn WPF a bit better including the MVVM pattern to encourage the separation of concerns between the view and the logic behind it.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a steep learning curve (to say the least!) but today I spent a bit of time looking into getting an Office-esque ribbon bar onto the main window of my dummy application. At first I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too sure, but I soon realised it&amp;rsquo;s not too dissimilar to any other button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connection problems in Visual Studio 2013</title>
      <link>/blog/visual-studio-2013-connection-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 12:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/visual-studio-2013-connection-problems/</guid>
      <description>Since installing Update 2 on the work laptop, I&amp;rsquo;ve been unable to check for available updates through the Tools &amp;gt; Extensions &amp;amp; Updates screen as it always timed out. If I continued working (without closing the IDE), it would eventually prompt me through the Notifications pane that it required credentials for the company proxy. Once I did that, it&amp;rsquo;d report updates etc. but over the last couple of days, that is no longer happening either.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>